

ABOUT ME

I am a Technology Enthusiast and I believe that Programming is my superpower. I am an Entrepreneur, a Programmer and an Educator. I have been running my own Software Development agency since I was in college. I have successfully developed over 20 web and app projects in the past 4 years.

In addition to coding, I have a knack for teaching. I have mentored over 10,000 students in multiple Programming languages and frameworks through various online courses on Udemy, UpGrad and MyCaptain and offline bootcamps in prestigious colleges including IIT Jammu and SCSVMV University, Kanchipuram.

You can find me reading a thrilling murder mystery or writing my heart out when I am not working.

GET IN TOUCH

Email:

aquib@tabdeel.in

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/aquibajani

Instagram:

@codewithaquib

Address:

2142, Tower 2, Prestige Tranquility, Budigere Cross, Bangalore - 560049

AQUIB AJANI

MENTOR | ENTREPRENEUR | DEVELOPER

WORK EXPERIENCE

Founder and Chief Vision Officer

Tabdeel Studios, Bangalore | *November 2017 - Present*

• Completed 20+ Web and App Design and Development projects in multiple domains for both start-ups and enterprises

Academic Xpert - C Programming and ADS

UpGrad, Bangalore | September 2020 - Present

 Recorded 25+ hours of content on C Programming and Advanced Data Structures and conducted LIVE sessions for BCA students

Learning Content Designer

MyCaptain by The Climber, Bangalore | *May 2019 - December 2019*

 Designed a comprehensive workshop framework along with making curriculum and content for multiple technical workshops

Web Development Workshop Mentor

MyCaptain by The Climber, Bangalore | December 2016 - Present

• Recognised as a Young Achiever in the fields of Programming and Web Development. Mentored 5000+ students on the platform.

National Director of Design and IT

Uddeshya India (NGO), Delhi | June 2017 - Present

 Responsible for maintaining the website and managing all other design and technical requirements of the organisation

Course Author

ChalkStreet, Bangalore | December 2014 - October 2020

 Designed and recorded content for 7 Technical Courses (Programming and Web Development) having 3200+ registrations as of October 2020

Web Development Intern

Awespicious Solutions, Nagpur | June 2016

Developed a Learning Management System using LearnPress

AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

Competition Finalist : First prize at NHRD EAGLES NEST Bangalore, a start-up idea-submission competition held in 2016

Winner, Community DevFest CodePlay: Third prize at a hackathon powered by HackerEarth, organised by CSI-VIT in 2016

Winner, Firefox OS App Days: First prize at an App-a-thon organised by Mozilla in graVITas'14, VIT's Annual Tech Fest

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Coding Languages:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, C/C++, Java, Python, Dart

Programming Frameworks:

Bootstrap, MERN/MEAN Stack, Flutter, Firebase, WooCommerce

Software and Tools:

WordPress, Wix, Shopify, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premier Pro, OBS Studio, Camtasia Studio, Canva, InVideo, Visual Studio, VS Code, GitHub, Microsoft Office

Public Speaking:

Conducted multiple on-ground bootcamps on Web Development in prestigious universities including IIT Jammu and SCSVMV University Kanchipuram, among others.

Spoken Languages:

English, Hindi, Marathi

UDEMY COURSES

Mastering the craft of UI/UX with Adobe XD

- Use Adobe XD to create wireframes and prototypes for website and applications
- 3 hours of video content

Bring your Instagram Stories to life with InVideo

- Learn simple, effective techniques to create beautiful marketing videos easily using InVideo
- 2 hours of video content

OTHER INITIATIVES

YouTube - Code With Aquib

https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK6XGH___4fpjne-gp5cYUg

Newsletter - The Code Report

bit.ly/thecodereport

PROJECTS

Unboxing Art - a complete EdTech solution

Android App, iOS App, Web App, Website and Admin Panel

- <u>Technologies Used</u>: Flutter, Firebase, MERN Stack
- Link: https://www.unboxingart.in

The Korner Shop - a complete Delivery solution

Android App, iOS App, Web App, Website and Admin Panel

- Technologies Used : Flutter, Firebase, MERN Stack
- Link: https://www.thekornershop.in

Glaming Beauty - Ecommerce Website

Ecommerce Website for cosmetics and beauty products

- Technologies Used : WordPress, WooCommerce
- Link: https://www.glamingbeauty.com

Uddeshya India - NGO Website

Custom Website about the NGO

- Technologies Used : Bootstrap, PHP, MySQL
- Link: https://www.uddeshyaindia.org

Teach our Teachers - Product landing page

Custom Website to test the Product-Market fit

- Technologies Used : ReactJS, Firebase, Bootstrap
- **Link**: https://teachourteachers-369a6.web.app/

Make Chaos - Website for an interior design firm

Website to showcase portfolio and generate leads

- **Technologies Used** : ReactJS, NodeJS, Bootstrap
- Link: https://www.makechaos.in

Tabdeel Studios - Website for my startup

Website to showcase portfolio and generate leads

- Technologies Used : WordPress
- Link: https://www.tabdeelstudios.com

EDUCATION

Vellore Institute of Technology (VIT University), Vellore

M.Tech in Software Engineering (5 years integrated) | 2014 - 2019

- Major Project : Analysing Project Outcomes for Reuse Potential and
- Predicting Project Metrics (accepted at SSIP International Conference)

 Mini Project: Prediction Model for Assisting Project Initiation and Execution
- **Final CGPA**: 9.36/10

Delhi Public School, Nagpur

10th and 12th CBSE Board | 2008 - 2014

- President's Cup for the Best All-Rounder Student awarded in class 12th
- Principal's Cup for the Most Disciplined Student awarded in class 10th
- Became the Vice Head Boy in class 11th
- Represented the school multiple times in numerous inter-school debates, elocutions and spell bee competitions
- Hosted multiple events and assemblies in intra-school events